Thomas Delaney

Senior Business Intelligence Developer/Analyst/ETL expert AWS Cloud, IT implementation Bangalore, India

"No one is good at everything but as long as you are focused on your core offering, you are gonna be great. I have worked in different companies and had different responsibilities to have a profile like that. I'm always interested in hearing from former colleagues, managers, or just interesting creative folk, so feel free to contact me if you'd like to connect."

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Business Analyst

Amazon Web services (June 2015-Current)

Senior Big Data Developer/Administration

IBM (May 2012- June 2015)

Hadoop/Java developer

SAP SE (April 2009-May 2012)

CERTIFICATIONS

BI tools (Tableau, IBM cognos) from JM Technologies Hyderabad(September 2013-December 2014). Big Data Developer/Administration from Inventateq, Bangalore (August 2008-Jan 2009) Advance Java from NIIT Jaipur.

PROJECTS

Name: Sales Data Analysis (Amazon web Services)

Role: Developer

Technology: Hadoop, Amazon Kinesis.

Description: Analysis of data using different big data tools to provide best customer offering.

Name: Predictive Analysis of Aviation Data (SAP SE)

Role: System analyst and team Leader

Technology: Tableau

Description: After data was analyzed, it was represented to the customer using BI tool to provide better

understanding and easy model.

Name: Online Shopping Website

Role: Back-end Developer Technology: Advance Java

Description: It provides an easy option to shop for the people and contains every possible brand, genres of

clothes.

PUBLICATIONS/RECOGNITION

- Published a paper on "Content Based Image Retrieval using Map Reduce, Hadoop" in International journal of science and technology.
- Reviewed a paper on "Business Intelligence: Concepts and Approaches" in MBM Journal.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master of Technology (2007-2009) Data analytics Aggregate- 77% BITS, Pilani

Senior Secondary (2002-2003) PCM Score- 81% St. Anslem's, Jaipur Bachelor of technology (2003-2007) Computer Science Aggregate- 76.3% MBM, Jodhpur

Secondary (2000-2001) Score- 9.6 CGPA St. Anslem's, Jaipur